<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Programming | Why / Why Not]]></title>
  <link href="http://kn-f.github.io/blog/categories/programming/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kn-f.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-11-16T15:24:50+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://kn-f.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[kn_F]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Not - Developer Block]]></title>
    <link href="http://kn-f.github.io/blog/2015/11/16/why-not-developer-block/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-16T15:04:10+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://kn-f.github.io/blog/2015/11/16/why-not-developer-block</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[Always the same old story: now I am able to program now not...

What makes the difference? And is the *problem* just for programming?
<!--more-->
You read a lot of stuff around about on self help, on what you should do to live better and so on. At first I looked at these for inspiration, to see if I could find a *help* for me, then I started realizing that all these methods work, but for those who wrote them.

One of the thing I learned is to listen to myself, to my needs. Sometimes my body or my brain was giving me hints: *tiredness*, *apathy*, *aggressiveness*, *muscular pains*&#8230;If you&#8217;re healthy you should not experience these, at least not for a sustained amount of time. Small side note: I&#8217;m being over generic on these terms because it all really depends on you, if you&#8217;re usually grumpy even an excess of happyness could indicate that something&#8217;s wrong.   

I&#8217;m sure you already experienced this. What did you do? Call it a day? Run and do something to distract you?
No, there&#8217;s no one fits all solution, only you can listen to what your body tells you and only you will be the one able to reply properly.

The more I&#8217;m aware soemthing&#8217;s not right with me, the easier it is to manage my developer&#8217;s block.
Now I just want to enjoy myself, I don&#8217;t have deadlines, huge expectations or problems of milions. It&#8217;s my hobby and when it starts to be frustrating, I stop, maybe I&#8217;ll come back later when I&#8217;ll have a freesher mind.]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why - Developer Block]]></title>
    <link href="http://kn-f.github.io/blog/2015/07/29/why-developer-block/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-29T10:09:24+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://kn-f.github.io/blog/2015/07/29/why-developer-block</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[In a [previous post](/blog/2014/12/29/once-i-was-a-developer/) I was extremely happy to say that my *developer's block* was no more.

Unfortunately that was just an illusion since just a few weeks later I fell again in it...and I was in that situation until very recently.
<!--more-->
It was a hard hit when I realized that I didn&#8217;t want, that I couldn&#8217;t work on my [project](https://github.com/kn-f/EmuProj) anymore: even if I had spare time I could not put down a single line of code, not even a &#8220;echo &#8220;Hello world&#8221;&#8220;. I felt like it was a too complex task, taking too much time, much more time than the one I had. I felt I didn&#8217;t have the skills (this one is actually true) to face the project I was working on.

Every time the same story and no matter how hard I tried, I just couldn&#8217;t do it. Then I found this [article](http://www.roguebasin.com/index.php?title=How_to_Write_a_Roguelike_in_15_Steps); it didn&#8217;t solve the problem but it started to move something inside me and I understood that I just didn&#8217;t had to *get it right* at first, I just had to start moving. And so I did: I listed all that was a blocking point for my *developer&#8217;s inspiration* and for each I proposed myself a solution. What came out is quite interesting (please keep in mind that I&#8217;m developing as a hobby)

1. *It is a very complex task*: The article on how to write a Roguelike game really helped: 
2. *I have to dedicate too much time to it*: I really didn&#8217;t tackle this point, I just realized that even dedicating 15 minutes every day to the project, it&#8217;s still progressing!
3. *I don&#8217;t have the skills*: True, nothing to hide here. But one of the reasons why I loved programming was because I could always learn something new. So here I am working on [AngularJS](https://angularjs.org/) and [Fat Free Framework](http://fatfreeframework.com/) looking on how I can *hidrate* an object.
4. *I need to get it right at first*: Uhhmm&#8230;really? Why? Once ready the project will not be usused by 1 million users at the same time, performances will be a problem but in a later stage. And the *product* itself? Who cares! I&#8217;m doing this as an hobby, if no one likes it, never mind, I&#8217;ve learned already so many things!

I&#8217;m sure in the future I&#8217;ll face this block again several times and for different reasons but as long as I&#8217;m aware of it and I know what the reasons are&#8230; :D]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Once I Was a Developer]]></title>
    <link href="http://kn-f.github.io/blog/2014/12/29/once-i-was-a-developer/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-29T10:50:33+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://kn-f.github.io/blog/2014/12/29/once-i-was-a-developer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[This is one of these days where I need to write. I'm sure I'll never publish this post but at least let's give it a go.
*Once I was a developer*, or at least this is what I think.
<!--more-->
I started &#8220;writing programs&#8221; when a I was about 6. I still have a program (but it should be more accurate to call it a composition of existing programs) that I wrote on paper when I was about that age. Nothing complex but at that time the *discovery* of the fact that I could *create* was incredible.

> 2/4/2015 - At that time I did not complete the post. I wanted to write that since a year or so I lost the will and drive to develop.
> Now it&#8217;s important for me to make the post public as finally it looks like I got back the inspiration!]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why - Music While Creating]]></title>
    <link href="http://kn-f.github.io/blog/2014/12/10/why-music-while-creating/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-10T19:12:50+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://kn-f.github.io/blog/2014/12/10/why-music-while-creating</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[Meh..:( Looks like I just lost the post...
[Koding](https://koding.com/) is briliant but needs a little bit of polishing to be a day to day tool.

I was very inspired while writing (yes I was listening to some music:[Neon Future I](http://open.spotify.com/album/3KYFjFzw34AhmlxQC8r5W6)) so probably it's better like this.
<!-- more -->
The point is that whenever I feel like I need lots of concentration, when I want ot be isolated from the world, I put on my headphones and listen to some music. Not always my favourite songs; actually depending from how I feel I can listen to *classical*, *heavy metal*, *electro*.

Every kind of music has a reason, each song has its piece of code, its part of the drawing that has inspired. The right music helps my creative flow, makes me feel like I&#8217;m just copying an existing script: no need to think, no need to review.

Then when the music ends and I check what I&#8217;ve done, the experience tells me that it&#8217;s not as good as it seemed to me when I was creating it. But still the influence of the music is there.

What&#8217;s your experience? Do you listen to music while creating?]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
